Portfolio Page

Yuliya TSOY

Full Stack Software Developer

Email: yuliya.tsoy2023@gmail.com

Mobile: 1(347)977-2476

PROFILE

Enthusiastic and challenge-driven bootcamp graduate from **Columbia University** with strong analytical and coding skills. Created 20+ web applications leveraging knowledge in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, React.

Skills obtained from my previous work experience: excellent communication, forward thinking, reliability, I applied to the 3 full stack projects I collaborated on within the bootcamp: references from my team members are available on LinkedIn.

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (fluent, professional)

100%

RUSSIAN (native)

100%

EDUCATION

TECHNICAL SKILLS

SOFT SKILLS

Feb, 2024 Columbia University,

New York, NY

Full Stack Web Developer

bootcamp

Aug, 2009 KIMEP University, Almaty, Kazakhstan.

Bachelor of Business
Administration

Languages: JavaScript , HTML, CSS Front End: React, jQuery, API, AJAX, JSON,

Bootstrap, PWA

Back End: Node.js, Express.js, Sequelize.js, JEST **Database:** MongoDB, SQL, NoSQL, IndexedDB

Deployment: Github Pages, Heroic **Methodologies:** OOP, MVC, Agile

Strong analytical skills

Agile thinking

Communication Skills

Detail-oriented Team Player

Adaptability

Fast Learner

PROJECTS

BINGO Fuel: Quickly Finds Nearby Gas Stations

Technologies used: Google APIs, Bulma.io, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

- · Github Code
- Deployed Link

Foodie Finds: was created to help people who are looking for restaurants that cater to their specific dietary needs. This app has a minimalist design and a user-friendly interface with a clear navigational structure that makes it easy to use. The user will be able to add their own review for a restaurant they've visited which will be saved to their account dashboard, as well as see other reviews of restaurants based off their filters.

Technologies used: TripAdvisor API, JavaScript, Handlebars, HTML, CSS

- Github Code
- Deployed Link

EXPERIENCE

October 2021 – Current Momentum Realty - Real Estate Salesperson, New York, NY

<u>Achievements</u>

- Increased Rental and Sales Closings by 15% and 11% respectively
- Created additional service of Property Management
- Improved network of real estate professionals within the company by 20%
- Consistently received high customer ratings: 4 and 5 star

December 2019 - October 2021 Living Source Residential - Real Estate Salesperson, New York, NY

Achievements

- Created new features in marketing properties, increased interactions with potential customers by 23%
- Found and evaluated investment properties improved network by 12%
- Analyzed short-sale and foreclosure stats that increased clients' financial returns and built trust
- Became top producer in the company within the first year

September 2008 - March 2013 Visor Capital Investment Bank - Sales Specialist, Almaty, Kazakhstan

<u>Achievements</u>

- By providing advisory client service increased referral rate by 62%
- Automated documentation flow on buying/ selling securities (stocks, bonds) that improved the number of closing deals a day by 27%
- Effectively handled client database: replaced inactive clients with the active ones
- Worked closely with top 10 Investment Companies in Kazakhstan, including Kazakh Telecom Securities, Halyk Bank Securities, National Bank of Kazakhstan and more
- Was promoted from entry level back-office specialist to front-office sales specialist in one year

INTERESTS

- Sports: love my morning runs along the beach
- Music: enjoy classical music (Beethoven, Chopin, Tchaikovsky); beginner piano player
- Socializing: when I am not coding, I spend time with my family and friends which provides lots of positive impact on my day-to-day life